

Josep Batallé

Researcher and Fullstack developer



jbatalle3@gmail.com



https://goo.gl/pK9ss1



https://github.com/jbatalle



ABOUT

MSc. Josep Batallé is a research engineer who obtained his Technical Engineer in Telecommunications at Rovira i Virgili University (2011) and his Master in Telematics engineering at the Polytechnic University of Catalonia (2013). He has been involved at i2CAT Foundantion in several European projects such as T-NOVA, GEYSERS, DOLFIN, CHARISMA, SESAME and OFERTIE involving the most relevant topics of the last five years: Network Function Virtualization (NFV), Software Defined Networks (SDN), Network as a Service (NaaS), 5G... Currently he is working in T-NOVA, taking care of the design and development of the core of TeNOR. TeNOR is a NFV orchestrator totally integrated with Openstack and Opendaylight (ODL) that follows the NFV ETSI standards.



Work Experience

Research and projects engineer, i2CAT Foundation

Nov 2013 - Present ② 3 years 3 months

- Designer and main developer of the NFV orchestrator for the T-NOVA project: TeNOR.
- Designer and developer of an OpenAccess platform for the CONTENT, SODALES and CHARISMA projects.
- Developer of multiple User interfaces (Dashboard) for several projects.
- Coworking with CISCO and Barcelona City Council in a proof of concept about FOG Computing.
- Technologies used: Ruby, Java, Javascript, MongoDB, ElasticSearch.

Intership, i2CAT Foundation

Dec 2012 - Oct 2013 ② 10 months

i2CAT Foundation is a non-profit research and innovation centre which promotes mission-oriented R+D+i activities on advanced Internet architectures, applications and services. The centre stands up for a new open innovation framework, fostering the collaboration between companies, public administration, the academic environment and end-users.

- Designer and developer of a Management interface for GEYSERS project. Implementation of the backend in a Network as a Service
- Proof of concept in NFV.
- Technologies used: Java, Javascript, HTML.

Intership, Artic-Group

Jun 2012 - Nov 2012 ② 5 months

Artic Group was a technology consulting and specialized in web presence and positioning.

- Development of several webs for different clients. Most importan client: solomoto.es
- Technologies used: PHP, Bash, HTML.



EDUCATION

MSc Telematics Engineering, Master, Universitat Politècnica de Catalunya (Barcelona)

Jan 2011 - Jun 2013

BSc Telematics Engineering, Bachelor, Universitat Rovira i Virgili (Tarragona)

Jun 2008 - Jan 2011



SKILLS

Backend: Ruby (Sinatra, Rails), Java (OSGI, Karaf, Spring, Hibernate, Maven), Python (Django), NodeJS, RabbitMq.

Frontend: HTML && CSS, Javascript(AngularJS, D3js, Visjs), PHP (Drupal, Wordpress).

Databases: SQL: MySQL, Postgre, NoSQL: MongoDB, EApache Cassandra, ElasticSearch.

DevOps: Ansible, Vagrant, Docker, OpenStack.

Networking: SDN (Openflow, ODL, vSwitch), NFV, IPv6.

Source control and CI/CD: Jenkins, Travis, Git, SVN.



$\textcolor{red}{\textbf{TeNOR}} \ , \ \textbf{http://github.com/T-NOVA/TeNOR}$

Published on: 2014-08-24

NFV Orchestrator platform developed by the T-NOVA project, responsible for managing the entire NFV lifecycle service. TeNOR covers the orchestration and lifecycle management of software resources that support the infrastructure virtualisation, and the lifecycle management of VNFs. The VNFs are deployed over Openstack.



 $\textbf{English} \ (\textbf{Fluent}) \ , \textbf{Spanish} \ (\textbf{Native speaker}) \ , \textbf{Catalan} \ (\textbf{Native speaker}) \ .$